[柯克] 舰长日志，星历5725.3
[Kirk] Captain's log, stardate 5725.3.
企业号正在前往阿尔法记忆
The Enterprise is en route to Memory Alpha,
一颗由联邦建立的小行星，专门作为中央图书馆
It is a planetoid set up by the Federation solely as a central library
包含联邦成员的
containing the total cultural history
所有文化历史和科学知识
and scientific knowledge of all Federation members.
与我们同行的是专家米拉·罗曼上尉
With us is specialist Lieutenant Mira Romaine.
她在船上监督新设计的设备的转移
She is on board to supervise the transfer of newly designed equipment...
直接从企业号到阿尔法记忆
directly from the Enterprise to Memory Alpha.
你是这艘船上
You're the sanest, the smartest,
最理智、最聪明、最漂亮的女人
the nicest woman that has ever come aboard this ship.
还有吗？
Anything else?
其他的我会…我会暂时保密
Anything else I'll... I'll keep to myself for the moment.
[柯克] 当斯科提这个年纪的男人坠入爱河时
[Kirk] When a man of Scotty's years falls in love,
他生命的孤独突然向他显露出来
the loneliness of his life is suddenly revealed to him.
他的整个心脏一度只为这艘飞船的引擎而跳动
His whole heart once throbbed only to the ship's engines.
他本来只能和飞船说话
He could talk only to the ship.
现在他眼里只有那个女人
Now he can see nothing but the woman.
我不认为斯科特先生会选择聪明的类型
I didn't think Mr. Scott would go for the brainy type.
我认为他没有注意到她有头脑
I don't think he's even noticed she has a brain.
斯科特先生
Mr. Scott.
斯科特先生？
Mr. Scott?
嗯？
Hmm?
一旦我们进入阿尔法记忆的可视范围内
As soon as we're within viewing range of Memory Alpha,
你和罗曼上尉将前往紧急手动监视器
you and Lieutenant Romaine will go to the emergency manual monitor.
你要准备直接转移设备到阿尔法记忆
You will prepare for direct transfer of equipment to Memory Alpha.
是的，舰长
Aye, Captain.
我们准备好了，长官
We're ready, sir.
上尉，请允许我为你即将到来的首次联邦任务表达祝贺
Lieutenant, may I offer my congratulations on what will be your first assignment for the Federation?
是的，祝你好运，上尉
Yes. Good luck, Lieutenant.
谢谢
Thank you.
舰长，我接收到一个高强度读数
Captain, I'm picking up a high-intensity reading.
是阿尔法记忆吗？
Is that Memory Alpha?
不，长官
No, sir.
抱歉
Excuse me.
放大倍数8
Magnification 8.
那是什么？
What is that?
一场风暴的迹象，舰长
Indications are a storm, Captain,
虽然我从未见过如此强烈
although I've never seen one of such great intensity
或奇怪的构造
or strange conformation.
读数？
Readings?
所有传感器读数都处于最大刻度
All sensor readings are at maximum calibration.
舰长，它正以曲速2.6靠近并且还在加速
Captain, it's approaching at warp factor 2.6 and accelerating.
检查一下
Check that.
没有任何自然现象的运动速度可以超过光速
No natural phenomenon can move faster than the speed of light.
它绝对超过光速，舰长
It is definitely doing so, Captain,
所以它不可能是一种自然现象
therefore it cannot be a phenomenon of nature.
开启护盾，黄色警报
Deflectors on. Condition Yellow.
黄色警报，长官
Condition Yellow, sir.
护盾已启动，舰长
Shields activated, Captain.
[柯克] 宇宙，最后的边疆
[Kirk] Space, the final frontier.
这些是星舰企业号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务：探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
寻找新生命和新文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇踏前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
星际旅行：原初
第三季第十八集
泽塔之光
The Lights of Zetar
苏鲁先生，带我们离开这鬼地方！
Mr. Sulu, get us the devil out of here!
全面扫描舰桥受到的干扰
Full scan on the disturbance that penetrated the bridge!
上尉，所有甲板，损坏报告
Lieutenant, all decks, damage report.
米拉！
Mira!
[柯克] 麦考伊医生来舰桥，紧急情况，紧急情况
[Kirk] Dr. McCoy to the bridge. Emergency. Emergency.
米拉！米拉！
Mira! Mira!
[外星人沙哑的说话声]
[Alien Croaking]
你在说什么？
What's that you're saying?
她受伤是因为摔倒还是骚乱？
Was she hurt by the fall or the action of the disturbance?
我不知道，你注意到了吗，斯科提？
I don't know. Did you notice, Scotty?
嗯，骚乱结束后，她就倒下了
Well, after the disturbance was over, she just collapsed.
医生，她怎么样？
How's she doing, Doctor?
我想她现在要醒了
Well, I think she's coming around now.
小心，慢点，你摔得不轻
Easy now. Easy. You had quite a fall.
我…我很好
I'm... I'm fine.
好不好我说了算，你想走到医务室吗？
You let me be the judge of that. Do you feel like walking to sickbay?
我很好，医生，真的，我很好
I'm fine, Doctor. Really, I am.
其他人好吗？
Is everybody else all right?
是的，很好
Aye, they are.
你只要按照麦考伊医生的命令做
You just do what Dr. McCoy ordered.
为什么？我觉得…
Why? I feel...
去医务室，上尉，那是命令
Get to sick bay, Lieutenant. That's an order.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
舰长，我也去医务室可以吗？
Captain, would it be all right if I went to Sickbay?
不，暂时留在你的岗位上
No. Stay at your post for the moment.
舰长
Captain.
乌乎拉上尉
Lieutenant Uhura,
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
损坏报告？
damage report?
所有电台都可使用，长官
All stations are operative, sir.
史波克先生？
Mr. Spock?
部分设备暂时出现故障
Some equipment was temporarily out of order.
我的传感器不起作用
My sensors were inoperative.
曲速引擎有任何损坏吗？
Any damage to the warp engines?
没有，舰长
None, Captain.
好的，从那场…风暴的行动来看
Good. From the action of that ... storm,
我们需要所有能获得的速度
we'll need all the speed we can get.
舰长，那不是风暴
Captain, it was not a storm.
舰长，在干扰中，阿尔法记忆在呼叫
Captain, during the disturbance, Memory Alpha was hailing.
我想回应，但我的手无法移动
I wanted to respond, but I couldn't make my hand move.
[契科夫] 舰长
[Cehkov] Captain.
瘫痪的不是手，是眼睛
It was not hands that were paralyzed. It was eyes.
我不能让眼睛向下看设置新的航线
I could not force my eyes to look down and set a new course.
[苏鲁] 不，是言语能力受到了影响
[Sulu] No, no, it was speech that was affected.
我发不出声音
I couldn't utter a sound.
史波克先生，解释一下？
Mr. Spock. Explanation?
只看结果，不看原因
Only of the result, not of the cause.
在每种情况下，大脑的不同区域受到影响
In each case, a different area of the brain was affected.
我们的自主神经功能处于某种形式的压力
Our voluntary nerve functions were under some form of pressure.
或者攻击之下
Or attack.
攻击也许是更精确的表述，舰长
Attack might be a more precise formulation, Captain.
罗曼上尉似乎最容易受到影响
And Lieutenant Romaine seems most susceptible.
读数一致吗，护士？
Are the readings corresponding, Nurse?
一切看起来都很正常，医生
Everything appears normal, Doctor.
谢谢
Thank you.
你在做什么，护士？
What's that you're doing, Nurse?
在电脑里记下你的反应
Recording your responses in this computer.
为什么？我没有值得注意的反应
Why? I haven't had a single response worth noting.
上尉，拜托
Lieutenant, please.
那，我有吗？
Well, have I?
上尉，这艘飞船上有430人
Lieutenant, there are 430 people aboard this ship.
你是唯一一个昏倒的人，我想知道为什么
You're the only one that passed out and I want to know why.
我也想知道为什么
I want to know why, too.
你是医生，你告诉我
You're the doctor. You tell me.
这对我来说是一种全新的体验
This whole thing is a new experience for me.
这对我们所有人来说都是一种全新的体验
This whole thing is a new experience for all of us.
你们都习惯了新的体验
All of you are accustomed to new experiences.
这是你们工作的一部分
It's part of your work.
我没有
I'm not.
她可能有些问题，麦考伊医生
She might have something there, Dr. McCoy.
这是她的首次深空旅行
This is her first deep space trip.
你知道它对人们有什么影响
You know how that affects people.
如果我们继续，斯科提，可能会得出这样的判定
If we can get on with this, Scotty, we might make that determination.
那么，现在告诉我
Now, then, tell me.
你昏倒前有什么感觉？
What did you feel before you passed out?
没有
Nothing.
没有？
Nothing?
绝对没有
Absolutely nothing.
上尉…
Lieutenant...
医生，我没有什么可以告诉你的了!
Doctor, there is nothing more I can tell you!
上尉，你完全不合作！
Lieutenant, you're being completely uncooperative.
你会把它放在我的记录里吗？
Are you putting that into my record? It's not true.
我会把真相放在你的记录里，要是我能知道的话
I'll put the facts into your record if I can get them.
好了，米拉
Come on, now, Mira.
我们必须帮助医生
We must help the doctor.
告诉我们发生了什么
Tell us what happened.
也许你可以向她解释一下
Perhaps you can explain to her
她希望在星际舰队中从事的任何职业
that any career she hopes for in Starfleet
都需要纪律和合作
requires discipline and cooperation.
嗯，我相信这就是上尉想要的
Well, I'm sure that's what the lieutenant wants.
她只是不理解
She just didn't understand.
是吧，姑娘？
Did you, now, lass?
对待病人的态度真不错，斯科提
With a bedside manner like that, Scotty,
你入错行了
you're in the wrong business.
记录被发送后，我会被遣返，不是吗？
When the record of this is forwarded, I'll be sent back, won't I?
才不会，太荒唐了
You will not. That's ridiculous.
习惯太空旅行需要一个过程
This getting used to space travel, that takes some doing.
不是每个人都能接受它
Not everybody takes to it.
那你呢？
Did you?
呃，我，那是不同的
Well, me, that's different.
我几乎是为它而生的
I was practically born to it.
我想继续
I want to continue.
你会的
You will.
你通过了星际舰队的初步考试
You passed your Starfleet preliminary examinations.
这只是习惯了你所谓的太空腿
And this is just getting used to what you might call your space legs.
我希望这就是全部
I hope that's all it is.
舰长，我已经绘制了风暴的路径
Captain, I've plotted the storm's path.
莱姆利先生
Mr. Lemli.
主屏幕投影
Main screen projection.
在目前的过程中，它将像击中我们一样击中阿尔法记忆小行星
On its present course, it will hit the Memory Alpha planetoid as it did us.
上尉，尝试警告阿尔法记忆那个现象的接近
Lieutenant, try and warn Memory Alpha of the proximity of that phenomenon.
给我一个ETA的影响
Give me an ETA for its possible impact.
我不能，长官
I cannot, sir.
它具有改变速度的能力
It has the ability to change speed.
长官，无法建立与小行星的联系
Sir, I'm unable to establish contact with the planetoid.
我在所有频率上呼叫，没有反应
I'm hailing on all frequencies. No response.
影响不大，舰长
It is of little consequence, captain.
阿尔法记忆没有护盾
Memory Alpha has no protective shields.
没有护盾？
No shields?
没有，舰长
None, Captain.
图书馆综合体组装时
When the library complex was assembled,
屏蔽行为被认为与其纯粹的学术目的相悖
shielding was considered inappropriate to its totally academic purpose.
由于记忆星球上的信息对每个人都是免费提供的
Since the information on the Memory planet is freely available to everyone,
特殊保护被认为是不必要的
special protection was deemed unnecessary.
好极了
Wonderful.
我希望风暴知道这个理由
I hope the storm is aware of that rationale.
正在靠近小行星
Completing approach to planetoid.
它已经超过了阿尔法记忆，舰长
It is already over Memory Alpha, Captain!
它的速度令人难以置信
Its speed is incredible.
它正在撞击小行星
It's hitting the planetoid.
我们在轨道范围内吗？
Are we within orbit range, Mr. Chekov?
正在降落
Making final approach.
上尉，试着警告他们…
Lieutenant, try and warn them ...
抱歉，长官，我无法突破干扰
I'm sorry, sir. I can't break through this interference.
史波克先生，有多少人在阿尔法记忆上？
Mr. Spock, how many people are on Memory Alpha?
它因使用该复合体的各个联邦行星的
It varies with the number of scholars, researchers, and scientists
学者，研究人员和科学家的数量而异
from various Federation planets who are using the complex.
[契科夫] 舰长，我们在轨道范围内
[Chekov] Captain, we are within orbit range.
锁定轨道
Lock into orbit.
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
[苏鲁] 它正在离开阿尔法记忆，舰长
[Sulu] It is leaving Memory Alpha, Captain.
传感器没有检测到阿尔法记忆有能量产生
Sensors give no readings of generated energy from Memory Alpha.
有生命读数吗？
Any life readings?
没有
None.
让我们看看下面发生了什么
Let's find out what's going on down there.
柯克呼叫轮机部，斯科特先生，报告
Kirk to engineering. Mr. Scott, report.
柯克呼叫轮机部，斯科特先生？
Kirk to engineering. Mr. Scott?
该死他到底在哪儿？
Where the devil is he?
斯科提，到舰桥报告
Scotty, report to the bridge,
到舰桥报告
report to the bridge.
传送室，待命，我会带一支登陆小队过来
Transporter room, stand by. I'm taking a landing party down there.
是的，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
我是斯科特
Scott here.
斯科提，你去哪儿了？现在在哪里？
Scotty, where've you been? Where are you?
在医务室
In the Sickbay.
你生病了吗？
Are you sick?
哦不，我只是在查看那个女孩
Oh no. I was just checking on the lass.
她会没事的，她没毛病
She's going to be fine. There's nothing wrong with that.
好的，听到你的预测，我松了口气，斯科特先生
Well, I'm relieved to hear your prognosis, Mr. Scott.
医生和你在一起还是我该去轮机部找他？
Is the doctor there with you or will I find him in engineering?
我是麦考伊，吉姆
McCoy here, Jim.
医生，女孩怎么样？
Doctor, how's the girl?
我认为她的状态很好
I think she's in good shape.
嗯，斯科特先生似乎同意你的看法
Well, Mr. Scott seems to agree with you.
你们两个立刻到传送室见我
The two of you meet me in the transporter room on the double.
[柯克] 舰长日志，补充，星历，5725.6
[Kirk] Captain's log, supplemental, stardate, 5725.6.
风暴已经清除了阿尔法记忆
The storm has cleared Memory Alpha.
它正以令人难以置信的速度远去
It is heading away at incredible speed.
我们一直无法与小行星取得联系
We have been unable to make contact with the planetoid.
它的沉默是不祥的
Its silence is ominous.
我们正传送下去调查
We are beaming down to investigate.
不知怎的，我觉得传送到黑暗中令人不安
Somehow I find transporting into darkness unnerving.
斯科提，你能不能给我们弄亮些？
Scotty, can you get us some more light?
恐怕这灯只能这样了，舰长
I'm afraid this light will have to do, Captain.
发电机不工作
The generator is inoperative.
损坏报告，史波克
Damage report.
银河系的灾难，舰长
Disaster for the galaxy, Captain.
中枢大脑受损，记忆核心烧毁
The central brain is damaged. The memory core is burned out.
银河系的损失可能无法挽回
The loss to the galaxy may be irretrievable.
舰长！
Captain!
附近有一个非常微弱的生命读数，舰长
Getting a very faint life reading in the immediate vicinity, Captain.
找到他，让他活着
Locate him and keep him alive.
我们需要更多有关这个敌人的信息
We need more information about this enemy.
这边，舰长！
Over here, Captain!
[咆哮]
[GROWLS]
老骨头，你能做点什么吗？
Bones, can you do something?
没有，吉姆
Not a thing, Jim.
罗曼上尉昏倒时发出了一样含混不清的声音
The same garbled sounds Lieutenant Romaine made when she fainted.
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
我确定
Absolutely sure.
柯克呼叫企业号
Kirk to Enterprise.
我是苏鲁
Sulu here.
立即把罗曼上尉传送下来
Beam down Lieutenant Romaine immediately.
史波克，你以前见过这样的东西吗？
Spock, have you ever seen anything like that before?
没有
Negative.
老骨头？
Bones?
她死了
She's dead.
她死于什么？
What did she die of?
严重的脑出血…
Severe brain hemorrhaging ...
由于神经系统扭曲
due to distortion of all neural systems,
自主神经系统溶解
dissolution of autonomic nervous system.
所有基本的人格因素，舰长
All basic personality factors, Captin.
攻击是彻底的
The attack was thorough.
其他人是怎么死的？
What did the others die of?
每个都有不同的大脑中枢被摧毁，原因不明
Each had a different center of brain destroyed, cause unknown.
你说，一个不同的大脑中枢
A different center of the brain, you say.
是的，舰长
Yes, Captain.
等我们回到船上，我可以用船上的电脑
I can be more detailed when we return to the ship
更详细地解释
and use the ship's computers.
米拉！
Mira!
舰长有几个问题
The captain has some questions.
是的，长官
Yes, Captain.
上尉，当你昏迷时，你在说话
Lieutenant, when you were unconscious, you were speaking.
我说了什么？
What did I say?
我不知道，我不熟悉这些话
I don't know. The words were unfamiliar to me.
听起来像什么？
What did it sound like?
听起来和技术员的遗言一模一样
They sounded exactly like the last words spoken by the technician.
什么技术员？
What technician?
我们在那儿发现一个奄奄一息的人
We found one person in there barely alive.
其他人都死了，我们…
The rest were dead and we...
上尉
Lieutenant.
上尉？
Lieutenant?
我们必须回到船上
We must get back to the ship.
为什么？告诉我为什么？
Why? Tell me, why?
那个风暴，它回来了
That storm, it's returning.
你怎么知道？
How do you know?
我知道，如果我们留下来，你会被杀的
I know. You'll be killed if we stay.
上尉，我向你保证，那个无法解释的现象正在远离这个星球
Lieutenant, I assure you, that unexplained phenomenon was headed away from the planet.
它可能正在寻找其他受害者
It is probably seeking other victims.
我和你说它会杀了我们
I tell you it will kill us.
企业号呼叫柯克舰长
Enterprise to Captain Kirk.
我是柯克
Kirk here.
舰桥，长官
Bridge, sir.
风暴再次出现在长距离扫描仪上并且正在快速接近
The storm has reappeared on the long-range scanner and is closing fast.
它的航线？
What's its course?
回到这个方向
Coming back in this direction.
把我们传送上去
Beam us up.
苏鲁先生，我是舰长，让企业号离开这里
Mr. Sulu, this is the captain. Get the Enterprise out of here.
等等，舰长，我们把米拉弄丢了
Wait, Captain, we've lost Mira.
推迟命令，苏鲁先生
Delay that order, Mr. Sulu!
让她稳定下来
Stabilize her!
有东西正在干扰传送信号，她停留在传送中
Something's interfering with the transporter signal. She's suspended in transit.
让我
Let me.
好了，苏鲁先生，带我们离开这里
All right, Mr. Sulu, get us out of here.
斯科特先生，检查传送装置控制器的紧急手动监视器
Mr. Scott, check emergency manual monitor for transporter control.
舰长，它正在改变航线
Captain, it's changing course.
绘制新航线，契科夫先生
Plot the new course, Mr. Chekov.
当前航线是126，标记20
Present course is 126, mark 20.
绘制它
Plot it.
目前的课程将把它带到我们的右舷，长官
Present course will bring it across our starboard side, sir.
史波克先生，你说过那个现象不是风暴
Mr. Spock, you made a statement that phenomenon is not a storm.
解释
Explain.
太空中没有已知的条件支持这种现象
No known conditions in space would support that phenomenon.
它是什么？
What is it?
船上的传感器有点问题
I'm having difficulty with the ship's sensors.
他们似乎受到这种现象的选择性攻击
They seem to be under selective attack by the phenomenon
就像阿尔法记忆上不幸的居住者一样
as the unfortunate occupants of Memory Alpha were.
那就不能用演绎推理的方法了
Then deductive reasoning will have to be substituted.
飞船的传感器目前正在运行
Ship's sensors are operating at the moment.
也许这个难以捉摸的生物现在会揭示一些关于它自己的东西
Perhaps the elusive creature will now reveal something about itself.
但我看到那些人死了，就在他们的位置上
But I saw those men dead, in their exact positions.
听我说
Listen to me.
我告诉过你太空旅行会在你的大脑中玩什么奇怪的把戏
I've told you what strange tricks a space trip can play on your mind.
现在就是这样
Now, that's all it is.
不，斯科提
No, Scotty.
在此之前，你有没有预见过未来的事情？
Have you ever had visions of the future events before this?
从没有过
Never.
如果你问我，没人有过
If you ask me, nobody ever has.
预见未来，纯粹是胡说八道
That seeing of the future, it's pure bunk.
你知道的，不是吗？
You know that, don't you?
我一直相信
I've always believed it.
那你是完全正确的
And you were perfectly right.
那么是什么，斯科提？
Then what is it, Scotty?
是什么让我害怕？
What's frightening me?
自从那场暴风雨袭击
Ever since that storm hit,
我有了这种奇怪的想法，这种恐惧感
I've had such strange thoughts, such feelings of terror.
太空，太空，这就是全部原因
Space. Space. That's all it is.
那我就不用报了吧？
Then I don't have to report it?
嗯，如果你想在医务室度过余下的旅行
Well, if you want to spend the rest of the trip in sick bay.
但这有什么好处呢？
But what good would that do?
麦考伊医生无法治愈它，就像他无法治愈感冒一样
Dr. McCoy can no more cure it than he can a cold.
舰长，它直冲我们而来
Captain, it's heading straight for us.
激活盾牌
Activate shields.
护盾激活
Shields activated.
契科夫先生，改航向143，标记3
Mr. Chekov, change course to 143, mark 3.
143，标记3
143, mark 3.
风暴的路线，苏鲁先生？
Storm's course, Mr. Sulu?
143，标记3
143, mark 3.
采取规避动作
Take evasive action.
规避动作
Evasive action.
右满舵，217，标记5
Hard starboard, 217, mark 5.
217，标记5
217, mark 5.
还跟着我们，长官
Still with us, sir.
左满舵，117，标记2
Hard port, 117, mark 2.
117，标记2
117, mark 2.
还跟着我们，长官
Still with us, sir.
还在接近吗？
Is it closing?
没有，舰长，保持距离
Negative, Captain. Maintaining its distance.
然而，它跟随我们执行的每个飞行动作
However, it is matching each maneuver we execute
我正在接收越来越大的能量
and I am receiving increasing magnitude of energy.
你的分析，史波克？它是什么？
Your analysis, Spock? What is it?
不是它是什么，舰长，而是他们是谁？
Not what is it, Captain. What are they?
里面有十个不同的生命单位
There are ten distinct life units within it,
都充满活力和活力
all powerfully alive and vital.
他们是谁？他们从哪里来？
Who are they? Where are they from?
如果不进行分析编程，就无法确定
Impossible to determine without programming for analysis.
显然，我们快不过他们
It's clearly we can't outrun them. What about shields?
我们能抵御他们吗？
Can we shield against them?
我认为企业号的盾牌不会被证明是有效的防御
I do not believe Enterprise's shields would prove effective defence.
一定有我们能用的防御
There must be some defense we can use.
我们正在与一个由生命单位组成的团体打交道
We are dealing with a community of life units.
它们的攻击以脑电波的形式
Their attack is in the form of brain waves
针对大脑，它们是相容的
directed against the brain, which is most compatible.
也许我们可以避免另一次攻击
Maybe we can avoid another attack.
乌乎拉上尉，打开所有通道
Lieutenant Uhura, open all channels.
接入通用翻译器
Tie in the universal translator.
史波克先生说它是活的
Mr. Spock says it's alive.
也许我可以和它谈谈
Maybe I can talk to it.
所有频道都打开了，翻译器已接入
All channels open. Translator tied in.
我是联邦星舰企业号的詹姆斯柯克舰长
This is Captain James Kirk of the USS Enterprise.
我们希望你没有恶意
We wish you no harm.
我们之间的身体接触对我这样的生命形式是致命的
Physical contact between us is fatal to our life-forms.
请不要再靠近我们的飞船了
Please, do not come any closer to our ship.
也许它不明白
Perhaps it did not understand.
舰长，记录到速度变化
Captain, change in velocity recorded.
[苏鲁] 他们掠过我们的右舷并在我们前面机动飞行
[Sulu] They are passing our star board side and maneuvering in front of us.
切换到前向扫描仪
Switching to forward scanner.
舰长，记录到速度变化
Captain, change in velocity recorded.
它加速了它的接近
It has accelerated its approach.
帮我，斯科提
Help, Scotty.
怎么了？
What?
抱紧我，又在发生了
Hold me. It's happening again.
不！
No!
米拉…
Mira...
也许它理解另一种语言
Perhaps it understands another kind of language.
红色警报
Condition Red Alert.
[警报声] 准备发射相位炮
[Sirens Blaring] Prepare for phaser firing.
米拉…
Mira...
不，斯科提！不！
No, Scotty! No!
[柯克] 锁定相位炮追踪控制
[Kirk] Lock in phaser tracking controls.
已锁定，长官
Locked in, sir.
调整相位器
Adjust phasers.
对其航线开火，不要击中它
Fire across its course. Do not hit it.
已锁定，长官
Locked in, sir.
开火
Fire.
反应，苏鲁先生？
Reaction, Mr. Sulu?
没有，长官，他们仍在接近我们
None, sir. They're still approaching us.
向船首开炮没有足够的震慑力
Apparently a shot across the bow is insufficiently convincing.
准备将相位炮锁定到团体的中心
Prepare to lock phasers into the heart of the community.
已锁定，长官
Locked in, sir.
开火
Fire.
斯科提！
Scotty!
米拉！
Mira!
米拉
Mira.
[苏鲁] 相位枪似乎已经阻止了他们的接近
[Sulu] The phasers seem to have stopped their approach.
他们保持不动
They're holding position.
锁定以进行再一次攻击
Lock in for another blast.
已锁定，长官
Locked in, sir.
斯科提[通过对讲机] 舰长！
Scotty [Over Intercome] Captain!
舰长，相位炮的射击正在杀死米拉！
Captain, the phaser shots, they're killing Mira!
杀死罗曼上尉？
Killing Lieutenant Romaine?
当你发射相位炮时，他们把她吓坏了，她瘫倒了
When you fired the phasers, they stunned her and she crumpled.
再开一枪，你就会杀了她
Another shot and you'll kill her.
马上带她去病房
Get her to Sickbay at once.
准备好开火了，舰长
Ready for firing, Captain.
取消那个命令
Cancel that order.
对那个外星生物的再一次攻击将杀死罗曼上尉
Another attack on that alien life-form will kill Lieutenant Romaine.
看起来是这样
It appears so.
如果要她活下来，我们就不能攻击
If she is to survive, we can't attack.
不直接攻击
Not directly.
计算机能否根据你积累的数据提供防御？
Can the computer supply a defense based on the data you've been accumulating?
不能，舰长
Negative, Captain.
我还无法为此收集到足够的数据
I have not been able to gather sufficient data for that.
舰长，只有一种可能的防御
Captain, there is only one possible defense.
如果我们能找到一个对外星生物致命的环境
If we can find an environment which is deadly to the alien form.
而将 女孩与其致命影响隔离开来
And yet isolate the girl from its deadly effects.
柯克舰长呼叫麦考伊医生
Captain Kirk to Dr. McCoy.
是的，舰长
Yes, Captain.
女孩身体够好可以接受询问吗？
Is the girl well enough to be questioned?
麦考伊[通过对讲机] 我可以在几分钟内让她准备好
McCoy [Over Intercom] I can have her ready in a few minutes.
尽快让上尉和斯科特先生去简报室
Have the lieutenant and Mr. Scott in the briefing room as quickly as possible.
带上所有可用的档案材料
Bring all available biographical material with you.
通话完毕
Kirk out.
史波克先生，跟我来
Mr. Spock, come with me.
对她宽容些，吉姆，她的状态很糟糕
Go easy on her, Jim. She's in a bad state.
我尽量
I'll try.
罗曼上尉
Lieutenant Romaine.
我不是有意不合作的，医生
I didn't mean to be uncooperative, Doctor.
当然，我告诉舰长了
Of course you didn't. I told the captain.
我们必须得知道正在发生的事情
We must get to understand what's happening.
我会告诉你我所知道的一切
I'll tell you everything I know.
飞船的调查程序有时会让新船员感到困惑
Ship's investigative procedures are sometimes confusing to a new crewman.
不要生我们的气
Don't let us upset you.
我绝对信任你们所有人
I trust all of you implicitly.
我想帮忙
I want to help.
这项调查是由两个事件促成的
This investigation has been prompted by two events.
首先是你在舰桥上昏倒的时候
First is the time you passed out on the bridge
其次是我们向正在攻击我们的那支部队
and the second is when we fired our main phasers into that force
发射主相位炮并重伤你的时候
that is attacking us and seriously injured you.
你不必担心伤害我
You mustn't worry about hurting me.
好的，那我们开始吧
Now, this is how we'll proceed.
史波克先生拥有所有我们能获取的有关攻击者的信息
Mr. Spock has all the information available to us about our attackers.
麦考伊医生可以查阅星际舰队关于你的详尽文件
Dr. McCoy has access to Starfleet's exhaustive files on you.
两者比较可能会揭示一些不太可能的联系
A comparison of the two may turn up some improbable connection,
这可以保护你和我们自己
which may protect you and ourselves.
好吗，各位？
All right, gentlemen?
麦考伊医生，你可以继续吗？
Dr. McCoy, will you proceed?
罗曼，米拉，上尉，出生地，3号火星殖民地
Romaine, Mira, Lieutenant, place of birth, Martian Colony number 3.
父母，莉迪亚·罗曼，已故
Parents, Lydia Romaine, deceased,
雅克·罗曼，星际舰队轮机长，退休
Jacques Romaine, chief engineer of Starfleet, retired.
史波克先生，你准备好讲讲攻击者的历史背景了吗？
Mr. Spock, are you prepared with the background history of the attackers?
是的，舰长
I am, Captain.
我已将所有可获得的数据输入了主计算机
I have fed all obtainable data to the main computer.
它应该准备好了提供任何可能的结论
It should be ready to supply whatever conclusions are possible.
谢谢
Thank you.
苏鲁先生，我们的朋友现在状态怎样？
Mr. Sulu, what is the status of our friends up there?
状态不变
Status unchanged.
他们仍然和我们一起，并保持相同的距离
They're still with us and keeping the same distance.
继续规避机动
Continue evasive maneuvers.
请随时通知我，通话完毕
Keep me informed. Kirk out.
医生，你有罗曼上尉的病历吗？
Doctor, do you have a medical record of Lieutenant Romaine available?
是的，舰长
Yes, Captain.
我想检查一下她的心理资料中的一些项目
I'd like a few items from her psychological profile checked.
有心身疾病史吗？
Any history of psychosomatic illness?
青少年常规发病率为偶尔
Occasional in teenage routine incidence.
是否有任何非自愿或无意识的心灵感应能力的证据？
Any evidence of involuntary or unconscious telepathic abilities?
没有
None.
任何病态或不寻常的移情反应？
Any pathological or unusual empathic responses?
不，舰长，没有移情作用
No, Captain, not empathic.
然而，对新的学习情境能作出极其灵活和顺从的响应
However, an extremely flexible and pliant response
这一特质非常明显
to new learning situations is highly marked.
继续，博士
Go ahead, Doctor.
在我们的相位炮中那个东西后
After our phasers hit that thing,
我对罗曼上尉进行了标准的斯坦曼分析
I gave Lieutenant Romaine a standard Steinman analysis.
结果可能很有趣
The results might be interesting.
嗯哼，继续
Mm-hm. Go ahead.
我们的斯坦曼与星际舰队的记录比较显示
A comparison of our Steinman with Starfleet records shows
罗曼上尉的指纹，声音分析
that Lieutenant Romaine's fingerprints, voice analysis,
所有外部特征都和以前一样
all external factors remain the same as before.
然而，根据两幅超脑电图
However, according to two hyperencephalograms,
她的脑电波模式改变了
her brainwave pattern has been altered.
这不可能
That's impossible.
据我所知就是这样
That's what I was taught.
但BCP与指纹一样始终不变
But the BCP is just as consistent as fingerprints.
让我们看看
Let's see it.
麦考伊医生，根据你的记录
Dr. McCoy, according to your records,
罗曼上尉没有表现出异常的心灵感应能力
Lieutenant Romaine showed no abnormal telepathic powers.
没错，史波克，但表现出非凡的顺从性
That's right, Spock, but exceptional pliancy was indicated.
这可能是一个因素
That might be a factor.
你确定这是正确的幻灯片？
And you're sure this is the correct slide?
是的，史波克先生，那是磁带卡座D
Yes, Mr. Spock. That is tape deck D.
米拉·罗曼上尉的脑回路模式
brain circuitry pattern of Lieutenant Mira Romaine.
先生们，它也恰好是磁带H
Gentlemen, it also happens to be tape H,
从外星生命单位那里获得的脉冲追踪
the impulse tracking obtained from the aliens life units.
查佩尔护士每一步都盯着，不会有错误
Nurse Chapel followed this every step of the way. There can be no error.
检查，史波克
Check it, Spock.
正如我所说，舰长，这是上次屏蔽运行期间获得的跟踪
As I said, Captain, this is the tracking obtained during the last shielded run.
电脑，进行详细对比
Computer, run a detailed comparison,
脑回路模式，磁带D和磁带H
brain circuitry patterns, tape D and tape H.
[计算机] 比较磁带D上米拉·罗曼上尉的脑回路模式
[Computer] Comparison tape D's brain circuitry patterns of Lieutenant Mira Romaine
和磁带H，外星生命单元的脑回路模式
and tape H, brain circuitry patterns of alien life unit.
相同
Identical.
真有趣
Fascinating.
没有错误
There has been no error.
麦考伊医生是对的，舰长
Dr. McCoy is correct, Captain.
思想的同一性正在发生
There is an identity of minds taking place
在外星人和罗曼上尉的思想之间
between the alien beings and the mind of Lieutenant Romaine.
他们的想法…正在变成她的想法
Their thoughts... are becoming hers.
舰桥呼叫柯克舰长
Bridge to Captain Kirk,
外星人不再保持距离了
the alien is no longer maintaining its distance.
继续规避动作，随时通知我，通话完毕
Continue evasive action. Keep me informed. Kirk out.
米拉一直试图告诉我，她提前看到了事情
Mira has tried to tell me all along that she was seeing things in advance.
你怎么不上报？
Why didn't you report it?
没人会报告太空病，我能想到的只有这个
You don't report space sickness. That's all I thought it was.
她看到了什么？
What did she see?
对船的第一次攻击
The first attack on the ship.
对阿尔法记忆的攻击和…
The attack on Memory Alpha and...
我们差点失去她的时候
the time we nearly lost her.
那些都是攻击者实施的行为
Those were all acts carried out by our attacker.
还有…
And...
是的，斯科提
Yes, Scotty.
还有什么？
What else?
我一时想，还有别的什么
I thought for a moment there was something else,
但我想我错了
but I guess I was wrong.
他错了吗，上尉？
Was he wrong, Lieutenant?
是的，还有一次
Yes, there was one other time.
你看见什么了？
What did you see?
我看到了斯科提
I saw Scotty.
在哪里？
Where?
我不知道
I don't know.
他在做什么？
What was he doing?
他快死了
He was dying.
现在我明白发生了什么
Now I understand what's been happening.
我一直在通过另一个思维看
I've been seeing through... another mind.
我被各种想法所淹没，而不是我自己的想法，它们控制着我
I've been flooded with thoughts, not my own, that control me.
哦，斯科提，斯科提，我宁愿死也不愿伤害你
Oh, Scotty, Scotty! I'd rather die than hurt you.
我宁愿死
I'd rather die.
现在好了
All right, now.
你在说什么死不死的话？
What's all this talk of dying?
他们三番五次地对我们发号施令
They've called the turn on us three out of four times.
任何人都不该遭受这些
That's a better average than anybody deserves.
现在轮到我们报仇了，我们要与他们战斗
It's our turn now. We'll fight them.
所以别再说什么死亡的事情了
So let's not hear anything more about dying.
[通讯器哔哔声]
[Communicator Bleeps]
我是柯克
Kirk here.
苏鲁[通过对讲机] 我是苏鲁，舰长，按照命令执行了所有的规避策略
Sulu [Over Intercom] Sulu, Captain. All evasion tactics carried out as ordered.
你取得了什么成功？
What success did you have?
没用，舰长
It's been useless, Captain.
以他们现在的力量，这一次他们会突破护盾的，舰长
At their present force, they will get through the shields this time, Captain.
曲速8，苏鲁先生
Warp 8, Mr. Sulu.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
他们很快就会到的
They'll be here very soon.
他们可能会像摧毁阿尔法记忆一样摧毁你我
They may destroy you and us as they did Memory Alpha.
你特别容易受到他们的意志的影响
You are especially susceptible to their will.
但我们有一次生存的机会
But we have one chance to survive.
不要反抗
Don't resist.
让他们开始通过你发挥作用
Let them begin to function through you.
如果我们能控制那一刻，我们就有机会
If we can control that moment, we have a chance.
你想试试吗？
Will you try?
告诉我该怎么做
Tell me what to do.
柯克舰长呼叫医学实验室
Captain Kirk to medical lab.
男人[通过对讲机] 这里是医学实验室，长官
Man [Over Intercom] Medical lab here, sir.
准备反重力测试装置
Prepare the antigrav test units.
我们走
Let's go.
注意，所有人员，注意
Attention, all personnel. Attention.
外星力量已经渗透进了这艘船
Alien force has penetrated the ship.
采取防御措施
Take defensive action.
[苏鲁通过广播] 所有人员注意，外星人已经渗透进了飞船
[Sulu On PA] Attention, all personnel. Attention, the alien being has penetrated the ship.
采取防御措施
Take defensive action.
战斗部署，安全条件3，入侵者警报
General quarters, security condition 3, intruder alert.
重复，战斗部署，安全条件3，入侵者警报
Repeat, general quarters, security condition 3, intruder alert.
一旦她进入重力室，所有舱门警戒
As soon as she has entered the gravity chamber, secure all ports.
别碰我，斯科提
Don't touch me, Scotty.
离远点
Stay away.
[低吼]
[Growls]
我们让她落入了敌手
We've lost her to them.
呆着别动！
Stay where you are!
这种状态下她可以杀了我们所有人
She could kill us all in this state.
她会的，除非我们能完成舰长的计划
She will unless we are able to complete what the captain has planned.
留在我们身边，米拉，请留下
Stay with us, Mira. Please stay.
我正在努力
I'm trying.
我想和你在一起
I want to be with you.
他们太强了
They are too strong.
不要迷失在他们面前，坚持住
Don't lose yourself to them. Hold on.
我是米拉·罗曼
I am Mira Romaine.
我将成为我选择成为的人
I will be who I choose to be.
我将会…
I will...
离远点，斯科提！
Stay away, Scotty!
他们和我在一起
They are with me.
他们会杀了你
They will kill you.
别让他们这么做
You won't let them.
她无法阻止我们
She cannot stop us.
你无法阻止它
You cannot prevent it.
米拉，米拉！
Mira. Mira!
舰长
Captain.
说话的不是米拉
That's not Mira talking.
我们现在必须直接对付他们
Captain, we must deal with them directly now.
当她还保留着部分自我时，我们可以与他们交谈
While she still retains partial identity, we can speak to them.
他们会用她的声音回答
They will answer using her voice.
我是星舰企业号的詹姆斯柯克舰长
I'm Captain James Kirk of the spaceship Enterprise.
你们听得懂吗？
Do you understand?
是的，我们能听懂
Yes, we understand you.
有个人我们已经寻找了一千年
We have searched for a millennium for one
通过他，我们能看，能说，能听，能过上自己的生活
through whom we can see and speak and hear and live out our lives.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我们来自泽塔
We are from Zetar.
那是所有类人生命都被摧毁的行星之一
That is one of the planets where all humanoid life was destroyed.
你不可能来自泽塔
You can't be from Zetar.
那里的所有生命很久以前就被毁灭了
All life was destroyed there long ago.
是的，所有的物质生命都被摧毁了
Yes, all corporeal life was destroyed.
那你是什么？
Then what are you?
泽塔最后100人的欲望、希望、思想和意志
The desires, the hopes, the mind and the will of the last 100 of Zetar.
我们生命的力量无法被消灭
The force of our life could not be wiped out.
万物皆灭
All things die.
在适当的时候
At the proper time.
我们的星球正在死亡
Our planet was dying.
我们决心活下去
We were determined to live on.
在我们计划离开的关键时刻，一场突如其来的最终灾难将我们击垮
At the peak of our plans to go, a sudden final disaster struck us down.
但我们生命的力量幸存了下来
But the force of our lives survived.
终于，我们找到了一个可以让我们度过余生的人
At last we have found someone through whom we can live it out.
你所占据的人的身体有自己的生活要过
The body of the one you inhabit has its own life to lead.
她会接受我们的
She will accept ours.
她不会
She will not.
她在为自己的身份而战
She is fighting for her own identity.
她的头脑会接受我们的想法
Her mind will accept our thoughts.
我们的生命将得到满足
Our lives will be fulfilled.
她会像阿尔法记忆上的人那样吗？
Will she learn the way the people on Memory Alpha learned?
我们不想杀人
We did not wish to kill.
但你确实杀人了
But you did kill.
不，反抗我们杀了那些人
No. Resisting us killed those people.
我们没有杀死他们
We did not kill them.
你的生存代价太高了
The price of your survival is too high.
我们只想要那个女孩
We only want the girl.
你们得不到她
You can't have her.
你们有权拥有自己的生活，而不是别人的
You're entitled to your own life, but not another's.
[米拉的声音] 生命被赋予了我
[Mira's Voice] Life was given to me.
这是我的，我想活下去
It is mine. I want to live it out.
我将会…
I... will...
女孩的生命读数正在接近泽塔人的，她快不行了
The girl's life reading is becoming a match to the Zetarians. She's losing.
[外星人的声音] 不要反抗我们
[Alien Voice] Do not fight us.
他们不会接受自己的死亡
They will not accept their own deaths.
强迫他们接受
They'll be forced to accept it.
你们都会死
You will all die.
舰长，如果我们不能完成计划
Captain, if we cannot complete the plan,
他们就会实施他们的威胁
they will carry out their threat.
我们必须让她进压力室
We must get her into the pressure chamber.
吉姆，你意识到杀死泽塔人所需的压力也可能会杀死这个女孩
Jim, you realize the pressure needed to kill the Zetars might kill the girl, too.
米拉不会杀我
Mira will not kill me.
[呐喊]
[Shouts]
我告诉过你她不会杀我
I told you she wouldn't kill me.
封锁压力室
Secure the chamber.
中和重力
Neutralize gravity.
泽塔人变得更强大了
The Zetars grow stronger.
失重状态已成为他们的自然状态
The weightless state has become their natural condition.
给装置加压
Pressurize the unit.
将压力增加到两个大气压
Bring pressures to two atmospheres
并每秒增加一个大气压
and increase one atmosphere per second.
继续增加压力
Continue increasing pressure.
压力，史波克，压力
Pressure, Spock. Pressure.
压力非常大，舰长
The pressure is dangerously high, Captain.
这可能会伤害她
It may damage her.
继续，史波克
Continue, Spock.
压力
Pressure.
我们做到了，吉姆，他们走了
We've done it, Jim. They're gone.
好了，米拉，他们走了
It's all right, Mira. They're gone.
他们走了
They're gone.
非常非常渐进地降低压力，史波克
Reduce the pressure very very gradually, Spock.
我们可能会消耗斯科特先生的耐心，医生
We may tax Mr. Scott's patience, Doctor.
完全静止地躺着，尽量不要移动
Lie perfectly still. Try not to move at all.
深呼吸，有规律地呼吸
Take deep, regular breaths.
别憋着
Don't hold it.
继续深呼吸
Continue to breathe deeply.
吸气
In...
呼气
out.
吸气
In...
呼气
out.
就这样
That's it.
你将在那里再待20分钟，
You'll be in there another 20 minutes,
所以请尽量放松
so why don't you Just try to relax?
现在我们拥有世界上所有的时间
Now we have all the time in the world.
老骨头，你能判断对罗曼上尉的长期影响吗？
Bones, are you able to judge the long-range effects on Lieutenant Romaine??
当涉及到人的个性时，预测是危险的
When the personality of a human is involved, exact predictions are hazardous.
特别是在涉及人类的情况下
Particularly where humans are involved.
然而，尽管星际舰队对上尉的判断是顺从
However, despite Starfleet judgment of the pliancy of the lieutenant,
她还是进行了英勇的斗争，以保持自己的身份
she put up a valiant struggle to retain her identity
我觉得这很令人鼓舞
and I find that encouraging.
麦考伊医生是对的
Dr. McCoy is correct.
虽然真相让人难以接受
While the truth was difficult to accept,
但当它被揭露时，她反应良好
when it was revealed, she reacted well.
我会说这次经历会加强她的整个自我意识结构
I would say her struggle in this would strengthen her entire ego structure.
你们有人会把斯科提对的她坚定不移的信念视为一个因素吗？
Would either of you credit Scotty's steadfast belief in her as a factor?
你是说…爱是动力？
You mean... love as motivation?
人类确实对这种特殊的情感要求很高
Humans do claim a great deal for that particular emotion.
我想这是可能的，然而…
I suppose it is possible. However...
没有然而，史波克先生
There are no howevers about it, Mr. Spock..
它就是，而且也将是她康复的一个因素
It was a factor and it will be a factor in the girl's recovery.
我是否可以认为你们俩都同意
Do I take it both of you agree
罗曼上尉不需要回星际基地进一步治疗？
that Lieutenant Romaine need not return to star base for further treatment?
嗯，我有理由相信工作是一种更好的治疗方法
Well, I should think work would be a better therapy.
合理
Logical.
柯克舰长呼叫斯科特先生
Captain Kirk to Mr. Scott.
我是斯科特，长官
Scott here, sir.
斯科特先生，罗曼上尉怎么样？
Mr. Scott, how's Lieutenant Romaine?
漂亮，舰长
Beautiful, Captain.
好的，斯科特先生
Yes, Mr. Scott.
我能否理解为她可以工作了？
Do I take it you say that she is fit for duty?
当然，舰长
Positively, Captain.
谢谢
Thank you.
柯克呼叫舰桥
Kirk to bridge.
我是苏鲁，舰长
Sulu, Captain.
苏鲁先生，设定到阿尔法记忆的航线
Mr. Sulu, set course for Memory Alpha.
罗曼上尉有很多工作要做
Lieutenant Romaine has a lot of work to do.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
嗯，这是企业号上首次
Well, this is an Enterprise first.
麦考伊医生，史波克先生和轮机长斯科特
Dr. McCoy, Mr. Spock and Engineer Scott
达成一致意见
find themselves in complete agreement.
我能承受这种压力吗？
Can I stand the strain?